[
    {
        "front": "Which dimensions define SAP Fiori?",
        "back": "Concept, Design, Technology"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the main principles of SAP Fiori?",
        "back": "Role-based, Adaptive, Simple, Coherent, Delightful"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which clients can be used for SAP Fiori?",
        "back": "Web Browser, SAP Business Client"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which platforms support the integration of SAP Fiori?",
        "back": "SAP Enterprise Portal, SAP Launchpad service, SAP Mobile Services"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which personalization elements can be assigned to user roles?",
        "back": "SAP Fiori Group, SAP Fiori catalog, SAP Fiori space"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which element has the application as target?",
        "back": "SAP Fiori app descriptor"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the app types of SAP Fiori?",
        "back": "Transactional, Analytical, Fact Sheet"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which services are provided by the SAP HANA platform?",
        "back": "Application Services, Integration Services, Processing Services, Database Services"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which areas were re-imagined in SAP S/4HANA?",
        "back": "User Experience, Business Processes, System Configuration, Database Models"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which applications can be used as entry point to create evaluations?",
        "back": "Query Browser, View Browser"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which are floorplans in SAP Fiori Elements?",
        "back": "Object Page, List Report, Overview Page"
    },
    {
        "front": "In which layers is metadata for SAP Fiori elements created?",
        "back": "Core Data Services, User Interface"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which layers of settings are available for SAP Fiori?",
        "back": "Personalization, Configuration, Customizing"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which elements of SAP Fiori can be assigned to business roles?",
        "back": "Spaces, Business Catalog Groups, Business Catalogs"
    },
    {
        "front": "For intent-based navigation, what does an intent consist of?",
        "back": "Semantic Object, Action"
    },
    {
        "front": "What can be used as target in target mapping?",
        "back": "Web Dynpro Application, Generic URL, ABAP Transaction, SAPUI5 Application"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is needed to define target mapping for an SAPUI5 application?",
        "back": "Component ID, ICF Path"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are catalog types in SAP Fiori?",
        "back": "Replicable, Standard, Back-End"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which task lists for SAP Fiori are run only once per ABAP system release?",
        "back": "SAP_FIORI_FOUNDATION_S4, SAP_GW_FIORI_ERP_ONE_CLNT_SETUP"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which ABAP Transaction can be used to analyze the intents used in target mappings?",
        "back": "/UI2/FLIA,/UI2/FLC,/UI2/FLPCA"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which system environments offer the UI theme designer?",
        "back": "SAP Enterprise Portal, SAP Netweaver Application Server ABAP, SAP Business Technology Platform"
    },
    {
        "front": "How can you enable adaptation at runtime for SAP Fiori Apps?",
        "back": "Target Mapping to runtime authoring plugin, User role SAP_UI_FLEX_KEY_USER, SAP Fiori Catalog /UIF/SAP_RTA_PLUGIN"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which terms are correct when talking about extensibility for SAP applications in a front-end server?",
        "back": "SAPUI5 Adaptation/Extension, SAP Fiori Elements Adaptation"
    },
    {
        "front": "How can you activate an extension for the SAP Fiori Launchpad(FLP)?",
        "back": "Target Mapping(/UI2/FLPD_CUST), Customer settings(/UI2/FLP_CUS_CONF)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which mobile application type can be created using swift?",
        "back": "Native App"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which mobile application type can be created using SAPUI5?",
        "back": "Mobile Web App"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which mobile application type can be created using metadata?",
        "back": "Cross Platform"
    },
    {
        "front": "What can be used as middleware to improve SAP Fiori for mobile?",
        "back": "SAP Mobile Services"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which native capabilities of a mobile device can only be leveraged when using SAP Fiori for iOS?",
        "back": "Touch ID, Facetime, iBeacon"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is needed to define target mapping for a Web Dynpro ABAP application?",
        "back": "System Alias, Web Dynpro application, Web Dynpro configuration"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is needed to define a target mapping for an ABAP transaction?",
        "back": "Transaction code, System alias"
    },
    {
        "front": "What does a KPI consist of?",
        "back": "Evaluation, Drill-down, Tile"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which shell configurations are available to adapt the header of the app?",
        "back": "Embedded, standalone, headerless"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which UI Clients does SAP Screen Personas Support?",
        "back": "SAP Business Client, SAP GUI for Windows, SAP GUI for HTML, SAP GUI for Java"
    },
    {
        "front": "What impact does UX have on monetary values?",
        "back": "Provides Productivity gains and increases data quality, Provides training cost savings, Reduces the number of change requests and user errors"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the principle of SAP UX strategy",
        "back": "New, Renew, Empower"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the ideas behind the SAP UX strategy",
        "back": "Design Strategy, New/Renew/Empower, Architecture and Technology"
    },
    {
        "front": "What impact does SAP Fiori have on Business?",
        "back": "Digitalization, Simplification, Leads to re-imagination of processes"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the current SAP UI tools?",
        "back": "SAPUI5 to implement SAP Fiori Applications, SAP Screen Personas to reduce the complexity of existing Dynpro and Web Dynpro ABAP Applications, Flexible UI Designer"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the current UI Technologies of SAP?",
        "back": "SAPUI5, Web Dynpro ABAP/Floorplan Manager, Dynpro"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the goals of the SAPUI5 Framework?",
        "back": "Provide a user interface technology for building and adapting client applicaitons, Provide an extensible framework for building desktop and mobile applications"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following steps are part of the discover phase in the DLD?",
        "options": {"A": "Scope", "B": "Test", "C": "implement", "D": "research", "E": "Synthesize" },
        "back": ["A","D","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following steps are part of the design phase in DLD?",
        "options": {"A": "Test", "B": "Validate", "C": "Prototype", "D": "Scope", "E": "Ideate" },
        "back": ["B","C","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the relation between the model and the controller in the standard MVC implementation?",
        "back": "The controller modifies the model and the model notifies the controller about changes"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which model types are supported by SAPUI5?",
        "back": "JSON Model, Resource Model, XML Model, OData Model"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which OData versions are currently supported by SAPUI5?",
        "back": "V2, V4"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which binding modes are supported by SAPUI5?",
        "back": "One-time, One-way, Two-way"
    },
    {
        "front": "In which base class implementation is the setModel function implemented?",
        "back": "sap.ui.base.ManagedObject"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following are best practices when developing a SAPUI5 app?",
        "options": { "A": "Descrbe your app using a set of metadata", "B":"Use the Synchronous Model Definition Syntax", "C": "Minimize the code in the index.html file", "D": "Make use of patterns", "E": "Use asynchronous model definition in your javascript code"},
        "back": ["A","C","D","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What approach gives you the most flexibility for your SAPUI5 app?",
        "back": "Using a component-based approach"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which control is used in the index.html file to support letterboxing if required?",
        "back": "sap.m.Shell"
    },
    {
        "front": "What configuration steps are necessary to define a navigation route?",
        "back": "Configure a route in the manifest.json, configure targets, navigation route must be assigned at least one target"
    },
    {
        "front": "Why does it make sense to use the navigation API or SAPUI5 and concepts such as eventbus or the navcontainer functions of the base application?",
        "back": "The API encures that the user of the app is able to store bookmarks for navigation targets, clearly seperates the navigation routes from application implementation"
    },
    {
        "front": "From which control does the sap.m.App control inherit navigation capabilities?",
        "back": "sap.m.NavContainer"
    },
    {
        "front": "Is it true to say that the sap.m.App control does not provide responsive behavior?",
        "back": "False, sap.m.App control provides responsive behavior"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the name of the aggregation of the sap.m.App control, or more precisely the name of the sap.m.NavContainer control, in which UI controls are aggregated?",
        "back": "pages, pages aggregations works as container for visual aspects like views, pages, or carousels"
    },
    {
        "front": "When is the master-detail pattern not recommended?",
        "back": "when you have to implement app wher user is able to apply complex filters on data in masterlist,or when user is able to display data in different facets such as charts and forms"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which modes are provided by the sap.m.SplitAppMode enumeration?",
        "back": "ShowHideMode, StretchCompressMode, PopoverMode"
    },
    {
        "front": "sap.m.SplitAppMode where master is automatically hidden in portriat mode",
        "back": "ShowHideMode"
    },
    {
        "front": "sap.m.SplitAppMode where master always shows but in a compressed version when in portriat mode",
        "back": "StretchCompressMode"
    },
    {
        "front": "sap.m.SplitAppMode where master is shown inside a popover when in portriat mode",
        "back": "PopoverMode"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the two aggregations provided by sap.m.SplitApp control to add page implementations?",
        "back": "masterPages, detailPages"
    },
    {
        "front": "What message types are known to SAPUI5?",
        "back": "Control Message, Server Message"
    },
    {
        "front": "How do you access the MessageManager?",
        "back": "it is a singleton and can be accessed by the getMessageManager function on the core object"
    },
    {
        "front": "In what configuration area of the manifest.json file can you activate automatic message creation?",
        "back": "sap.ui5"
    },
    {
        "front": "What layout control is used to achieve flexible and responsive layouts?",
        "back": "Grid"
    },
    {
        "front": "What aspects of the runtime environment can be accessed by the Device API of SAPUI5?",
        "back": "Operating System, Screen size, Orentation change, Touch-specific features"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the different content densities provided by SAPUI5?",
        "back": "cozy, condensed, compact"
    },
    {
        "front": "Content Density factor: Displays controls with dimensions large enough to enable fingertip interaction, idead for touch devices",
        "back": "cozy"
    },
    {
        "front": "Content Density factor: Reduces the dimensions of the controls, allowing more information to be displayed on the UI, ideal for devices operated by mouse and keyboard",
        "back": "compact"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the best approach to showing a UI control on a desktop only, and not on a mobile device?",
        "back": "Use standard CSS class sapUiVisibleOnlyOnDesktop"
    },
    {
        "front": "You want to define a property with the name width to enhance a standard UI5 control. The property should hold the current width of the UI control. What is the best approach to dfining the type of such a property?",
        "back": "Define the property width of the type sap.ui.core.CSSSize"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which function must be called inside a control renderer to add the control ID to the DOM tree and support eventing?",
        "back": "writeControlData"
    },
    {
        "front": "What to do implementing your own control renderer?",
        "back": "You must implement a class that is derived from sap.ui.core.Renderer, the implementation should use the AMD syntax and it is also necessary to assign the renderer implementation to the renderer property of your UI control implementation."
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following aspects are true for SAPUI5 UI element",
        "options": {"A": "A UI element has an API", "B": "A UI element does not have a renderer", "C": "A UI element has a renderer", "D": "A UI element can have events"},
        "back": ["A","B","D"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the base class for all UI controls in SAPUI5?",
        "back": "sap.ui.core.Control"
    },
    {
        "front": "How can a renderer access the associated elements?",
        "back": "SAPUI5 provides functions to access all properties, associations, and aggregations"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which file contains the initialization code for the UI Library?",
        "back": "library.js"
    },
    {
        "front": "What method is called inside library.js file?",
        "back": "sap.ui.getCore().loadLibrary"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following statements are true with respect to QUnit?",
        "options": {"A": "Supports only synchronous testing out of the box", "B": "QUnit is JavaScript unit and integration test framework", "C": "Supports asynchrounous tests out-of-the-box", "D": "Is capable of testing any generic JavaScript Code"},
        "back": ["B","C","D"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Does QUnit support SAPUI5 view tests?",
        "back": "No, UI tests must use OPA5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following statements are true with regard to OPA5?",
        "options": {"A": "Can be used for user interaction tests", "B": "Can be used for SAPUI5 integration tests", "C": "Is a view controller test framework", "D": "Provides the possibility to test navigation"},
        "back": ["A","B","D"]
    },
    {
        "front": "When do you need to work with local data?",
        "back": "When working with static data, to perform quick test without creating live entities on the back-end server"
    },
    {
        "front": "What query option is needed to access the data of an entity in the JSON format?",
        "back": "$format=json"
    },
    {
        "front": "Where is the best place to store local data when using the SAP Business Application Studio",
        "back": "localService and mockdata folder"
    },
    {
        "front": "What class in the SAPUI5 API supports back-end mock up and is recommended by SAP?",
        "back": "sap.ui.core.util.MockServer"
    },
    {
        "front": "What parameter is needed when instantiating a MockServer object?",
        "back": "rootUri"
    },
    {
        "front": "What parameter must you provide when calling the simulate function of the mock server?",
        "back": "The full qualified path to the local metadata file and the folder where the model data are stored locally."
    },
    {
        "front": "What type of concurrency control is offered by OData?",
        "back": "Optimistic concurrency control"
    },
    {
        "front": "How does the OData Model handle XRSF tokens?",
        "back": "The OData Model fetches the token while reading the metadata and sends the token automatically in each write request header."
    },
    {
        "front": "What is returned by the function createEntry?",
        "back": "A binding context Object"
    },
    {
        "front": "When do you use deep insert?",
        "back": "When working with hierarchical data where the data can only be stored in the full hierarchy"
    },
    {
        "front": "What method must be implemented on the back end to support deep inserts?",
        "back": "CREATE_DEEP_ENTITY"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which function do you call on the ODataModel to trigger a deep insert?",
        "back": "create"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the namespace in which the smart controls are bundled?",
        "back": "sap.ui.comp"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which aggregation is used to overwrite the standard behavior of a SmartField control?",
        "back": "configure"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAP Fiori elements?",
        "back": "No JavaScript UI Coding, Provides designs for UI patterns and predefined templates, the apps are based on OData services and use annotations."
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following describe benefits of SAP Fiori elements?",
        "back": "Consistent UI Design, Less Support Effort"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following SAP Fiori element based UIs are currently available?",
        "options":{"A": "Wizard Form", "B": "List Report", "C": "Master-Detail", "D": "Overview Pages", "E": "Object Page" },
        "back": ["B", "D","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Which UI annotation is used in the object page to display the object header?",
        "back": "UI.headerInfo"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which UI annotation is used to declare a field for the smart filter template?",
        "back": "UI.selectionField"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is meant by the phrase 'SAPUI5 supports modification free enhancements'? ",
        "back": "The delivered standard application remains unchanged, hence the extension is considered to be modification free"
    },
    {
        "front": "Is it possible to add an extension point in the component implementation?",
        "back": "No, Extension points are only supported in views."
    },
    {
        "front": "To what namespace is the ExtensionPoint class assigned?",
        "back": "sap.ui.core"
    },
    {
        "front": "What types of extensions/replacements are supported by SAPUI5",
        "back": "View Replacement, View modification, Replace Service, Implement UI Controller hooks"
    },
    {
        "front": "When you implement a controller extension and you implement onInit and onAfterRendering functions in the extension, when are they called?",
        "back": "After the corresponding functions from the standard controller"
    },
    {
        "front": "How is the extension type called to hide UI controls?",
        "back": "View Modification"
    },
    {
        "front": "What best describes a commit?",
        "back": "With every commit, GIT takes a snapshot of the current state of the underlying files."
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the main states of a file in GIT?",
        "back": "Commited, Modified, Changed"
    },
    {
        "front": "In which state are the files in GIT when a remote repository is cloned?",
        "back": "Tracked and unmodified"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the result of a GIT Reset?",
        "back": "Returns a project back to the previous state"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the result of a GIT revert?",
        "back": "Undoes a committed snapshot"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the result of a GIT Clean?",
        "back": "Removes all untracked files from the working directory"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is a GIT branch?",
        "back": "A GIT Branch represents an independent line of development."
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following statements are true about the merge functionality in GIT?",
        "options": {"A": "A merge deltes the content of a branch", "B": "Allows merging of two local branches into on local branch", "C": "Allows integration of a branch into another branch"},
        "back": ["A"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following information about an OData service should be provided as an annotation?",
        "options": {"A": "The entities of an OData service", "B": "Properties of an Entity Set/Collection", "C": "The position for each field in a list report", "D": "Data type for each property in an entity set/connection"},
        "back": ["C"]
    },
    {
        "front": "The combination of Term/Target is unique, that means for an Entity or a field, every term can be used only once.",
        "back": "false, the combination of term/target is not unique"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following templates display only one business entity?",
        "options": {"A": "List Report", "B": "Object Page", "C": "Overview Page", "D": "Analytic List Page"},
        "back": ["B"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Using SAP S/4HANA 1610 with ABAP 7.51, which of the following templates can you use for SAP Fiori elements?",
        "options": {"A": "List Report", "B": "Object Page", "C": "Overview Page", "D": "Analytic List Page"},
        "back": ["A","B","C"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Which info will be used for creating a destination in SAP BTP for SAP Fiori elements development?",
        "options": {"A": "Virtual name in SAP Cloud Connector", "B": "Internal name in SAP Cloud Connector", "C": "External name in SAP Cloud Connector", "D": "Internal address of SAP Backend Server"},
        "back": ["A"]
    },
    {
        "front": "When creating a CDS view, the SQL view name and view name for CDS must be identical",
        "back": "False"
    },
    {
        "front": "Steps needed to create an association in CDS and expose it?",
        "back": "Declare an association using 'association to' statement, Expose the association by writing its name in projection list"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the limitations of publishing CDS as OData service by adding a @OData.publish:true",
        "back": "Cannot Change names of entity sets, Only 1 level is taken into consideration when exposing associations, No customized ABAP code in SAP Gateway"
    },
    {
        "front": "In which cases, is a local annotation better than a CDS annotation?",
        "back": "Complex UI relevant annotations, You want to use annotations which are not supported by your current ABAP version"
    },
    {
        "front": "For a list report, which annotation is used to describe the name of business entity displayed on the report?",
        "back": "@UI.headerInfo.typeNamePlural"
    },
    {
        "front": "How can you hide columns when the list report is accessed by a movile phone?",
        "back": "Set UI.lineItem.importance for fields as #LOW or @Medium"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the use of the annotation @UI.hidden?",
        "back": "Prevent a column selected by user when customizing table settings."
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of followin description about search field is NOT true",
        "options": {"A": "The search field is searching on more than one data field", "B": "There is only one search field per list report", "C": "The search field searches for only one data field", "D": "Search field support fuzzy search"},
        "back": ["C"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Avaialbe options for creating a value help for a selection field",
        "back": "By adding a foreign key annotation, By adding a value help annotation"
    },
    {
        "front": "When running a list report, users can only filter data using fields provided as selection fields by developer",
        "back": "False"
    },
    {
        "front": "What steps needs to be done in manifest.json if you need to hide variant function in a list report?",
        "back": "Add setting to enable smart Variant Management, Set setting variantManagementHidden to True"
    },
    {
        "front": "How do you set a field as the title for a business entity?",
        "back": "Add @UI.headerInfo.title.value for the CDS view and reference it to the field"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which types are supported as header facets for an object page?",
        "back": "Field Group Facet, Plan Text Facet, Rating Indicator Facet"
    },
    {
        "front": "To add a header facet, you should use @UI.HeaderFacet annotation and put it before the define statement of your CDS View",
        "back": "False"
    },
    {
        "front": "The CDS annotation @UI.facet is used to",
        "back": "Create a Header Facet, Create a collection facet which is displayed as section, Create a reference under collection facet"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following properties are relevant to the type of facet?",
        "back": "purpose, type"
    },
    {
        "front": "If your back end system is based on ABAP 7.50, which are available ways of using facets?",
        "back": "Declare both field groups and facet as local annotation using BAS, Declare field group in CDS View declare facets as local annotation using BAS"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the options for external navigation?",
        "back": "Navigation to URL(As a Link), Navigation to intent(As a Link), Navigation to Intent(As a Button)"
    },
    {
        "front": "What can you do by editing manifest.json?",
        "options": {"A": "Disable Object page", "B": "Add object pages as sub page under an object page", "C": "Define facets on Object Page", "D": "Disable List Report"},
        "back": ["A", "B"]
    },
    {
        "front": "The field indicate criticality should be hidden because it means nothing to end user",
        "back": "True"
    },
    {
        "front": "What steps aer used to display a field as a rating indicator?",
        "back": "Set type of line item #AS_DATAPOINT, add a @UI.datapoint to the field and set visualization to #RATING"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the differences between analytical entity set and normal entity set from an OData consumer perspective?",
        "back": "Analytical Entity Set: Generates a new field for primary key, returns all data needed to analyze client, analyzes the use of the database and runs faster when SAP HANA is used as database compared to a normal entity set"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAP Fiori elements support write operations, if the back end service is written by CDS working with BOPF",
        "back": "True"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following types are types of cards in an overview page?",
        "options": { "A":"List", "B":"Link List", "C":"Analytic", "D":"Table", "E":"Stack"},
        "back": ["A","B","C","D","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Which areas are part of analytic list page",
        "back": "Title Area, Visual Filters, Content Area"
    },
    {
        "front": "In an Analytic List Page, the user can filter data by selecting some points in the chart",
        "back": "True"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is described as the persons preceptions and response that result from the use or anticipated use of a product, syste, or service?",
        "back": "User Experience"
    },
    {
        "front": "What does effectiveness mean in the relation to the user interface?",
        "back": "The accuracy and completeness with which specified users can achieve specified goals in specific environments."
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following can be used for usability assessment?",
        "options":{"A": "Heuristic Evaluation", "B": "User Testing", "C": "User Observation", "D": "Questionaires"},
        "back": ["A", "B", "D"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What application type is implemented to analyze huge amount of data with diagrams?",
        "back": "Analytical"
    },
    {
        "front": "For what platforms is SAP Fiori Design Language defined?",
        "back": "Web, Native Mobile, Conversational UX"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the preferred technology to implement SAP Fiori Applications?",
        "back": "SAPUI5"
    },
    {
        "front": "What three key aspects are important when talking about innovation?",
        "back": "Feasibility, Viability, Desirability"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the main spaces in the design thinking process?",
        "back": "Problem Space, Solution Space"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are common design thinking brainstorming rules?",
        "back": "Be visual, Fail early and often"
    },
    {
        "front": "What do you focus on when it comes to decomposition and re-composition?",
        "back": "The person's tasks that should be supported by the application"
    },
    {
        "front": "The SAP Fiori Design Guidelines are available for various device types. For what device types are the design guidlines avialable?",
        "back": "Sap Fiori for Android, SAP Fiori for Web, SAP Fiori for iOS"
    },
    {
        "front": "What content desnity is used for touch-enabled devices?",
        "back": "Cozy Form factor"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which different app types can be found in SAP Fiori?",
        "back": "Conceptual, Technical"
    },
    {
        "front": "What technical application types are defined for SAP HANA?",
        "back": "Transactional, Fact Sheets, Analytical"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following statements are correct with respect to the SAP Business Application Studio?",
        "options": {"A": "BAS is a development environment for SAP ABAP", "B": "BAS is a browser based development environment", "C": "BAS provides application templates as a foundation of highly efficient app development", "D": "BAS is based on an opensource IDE", "E": "BAS provides WYSIWYG tooling"},
        "back": ["B","C","D","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What is true of the SAP Business Technology Platform SAP Business Application Studio?",
        "options": {"A": "It requires 0 installation", "B": "Provides only SAP Cloud Programming Capabilities", "C": "It is updated on a regular basis.", "D": "Does only provide one workspace for project organization"},
        "back": ["A", "C"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the main artefacts of an SAPUI5 application",
        "back": "Models, Views, Controllers"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the tasks of the controller in the MVC implementation?",
        "back": "Modfies the model, Modifies the view via API"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following statements are talking about the SAP Fiori app architecture?",
        "options": {"A": "SAP Fiori apps are implemented using the component-based approach", "B": "apps have an index.html file that is used for FLP integration", "C": "apps need to have an app descriptor and describes the applications metadata", "D": "apps should use the SAPUI5 core as a place to hold app data models"},
        "back": ["A", "C"]
    },
    {
        "front": "SAPUI5 provides two different router implementations. What router class is used in SAP Fiori apps as a router or as a router base class, when you want to implement your own router?",
        "back": "sap.m.routing.Router"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the main configuration objects of the routing configuration?",
        "back": "config, routes, targets"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following artefacts are contained in the OData URL structure?",
        "options": {"A": "Service Root URI", "B": "Header Data", "C": "Resource Path", "D": "Query Options"},
        "back": ["A","C","D"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What of the following are important technologies of the ABAP programming model of SAP Fiori?",
        "options": {"A": "SAPUI5 and SAP Fiori Elements", "B": "IABAP Core Data Services", "C": "BAdi and RFC", "D": "SAP HANA"},
        "back": ["A","B","D"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What aggregations are defined by the sap.suite.ui.commons.ChartContainer?",
        "back": "content, dimensionsSelector, customicons"
    },
    {
        "front": "What main aspects does the developer have to configure for a sap.viz.ui5.controls.VizFrame control?",
        "back": "Dataset, DimensionsDefinition, MeasureDefinition, Feed"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the idea behind the golden rule of having one common UX?",
        "back": "Having a common UX reduces training costs and increases the quality of data"
    },
    {
        "front": "Why is it advisable to not use a custom CSS file in your SAP UI5 applications?",
        "back": "Having one central design created with the theme designer is very effcient when something needs to be changed at the client interface, it is easier to handle."
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following should you avoid with regard to the golden rule 'Every SAP Fiori app must run as a web app'",
        "options": {"A": "Absolute URLs generated in front or back-end", "B": "Using SAPUI5", "C": "Hard dependencies between apps", "D": "Calling UI2 services directly instead of using APIs", "E": "Use of platform specific functionality without availability check"},
        "back": ["A","C","D","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Which factors are key to the user experience with user assistence?",
        "back": "Instant, Context-Sensitive, Seamless"
    },
    {
        "front": "What areas are mandatory in the tile layout?",
        "back": "Header Area, Content Area"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following components are part of the SAP Fiori Launchpad?",
        "options": {"A": "Shell services", "B": "UI2 Services", "C": "Shell Container", "D": "Runtime Container", "E": "Runtime Configuration"},
        "back": ["A","C","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What types of services are known or supported by the FLP",
        "back": "Platform-specific services, Platform-independent services"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following make up the configuration of a tile for launcing a SAP Fiori app of type SAPUI5 in the FLPD",
        "options": {"A": "Semantic object", "B": "Launchpad creation via LPD_CUST", "C": "Target Mapping", "D": "Tile Configuration", "E": "Tile implementation"},
        "back": ["A","C","D"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What transaction is used to creat an semantic object for customer configuration?",
        "back": "/UI2/SEMOBJ"
    },
    {
        "front": "What application in the SAP Fiori Launchpad helps the user to find applications that are available to the user?",
        "back": "Application Finder"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following layouts, are described in version 1.48 of the Guidelines?",
        "options": {"A": "Dynamic Page", "B": "Full-Screen", "C": "Split Screen", "D": "Flexible Column Layout","E": "MobileDeviceLayout"},
        "back": ["A","D"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What aspects should be considered in deciding which layout template to use?",
        "back": "When deciding which template to use for your app, you need to consider what the user wants to achieve when working in the app, it is helpful to answer questions on the nature of the tasks"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which types of application can use the dynamic page layout?",
        "back": "You can use the dynamic page layout for any kind of application"
    },
    {
        "front": "When should you not use the dynamic page layout?",
        "back": "You are planning to use SAP fiori elements, such as the list report, analytical list page, overview page, or object page, which already incorporates the dynamic page layout. You want to implement an initial page or object page floor plan these floor plans already incorporate snapping header and footer toolbar features, the behavior is comparable to the dynamic page behavior, but the technical foundation is different. You only need to display a small amount of information, in this case use a dialog instead, if you cannot avoid using the dynamic page layout, use letterboxing to mitigate the issue."
    },
    {
        "front": "When do you use the flexible-column layout?",
        "back": "You want to create a master-detail or mater-detail-detail scenario in which the user can drill down or navigate."
    },
    {
        "front": "How many columns are supported by the flexible-column layout?",
        "back": "3"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is a SAP Fiori floorplan?",
        "back": "A floorplan is a UI pattern that provides consistent UX"
    },
    {
        "front": "When do you have to implement the SAP Fiori floorplan Initial page",
        "back": "The initial page floorplan is used when the user needs to navigate to a single object."
    },
    {
        "front": "What SAPUI5 control is used as a starting point to implement the initial page?",
        "back": "sap.m.Input"
    },
    {
        "front": "What problem is solved by the list report floorplan?",
        "back": "You want to display a large collection of items and the user can take some action."
    },
    {
        "front": "What problem is solved by the object page floorplan?",
        "back": "You want to display all the information of a simple or complex object with diffent facets in a responsive way"
    },
    {
        "front": "What problem is sovled by the worklist report floorplan?",
        "back": "You want to display a collection of items and process them or delegate them to someone else"
    },
    {
        "front": "What problem is solved by the wizard floorplan?",
        "back": "The user must process a long and unfamilar task"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the nature of the overview page floorplan?",
        "back": "You want to show all information that is needed by the user on a single page, based on a user specific domain or role."
    },
    {
        "front": "When do you not use the overview page floorplan?",
        "back": "A high-level or birds-eye view of an application content is sufficient. You want to show information about one object only, in this case use the object page instead. You just represent one application and less than three cards."
    },
    {
        "front": "What UI control can be used to define a hook to exten an application?",
        "back": "sap.ui.core.ExtensionPoint"
    },
    {
        "front": "What ways are there of extending or modifying a SAPUI5 view?",
        "back": "View Extension, View Replacement, View Modificaiton"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the goal of every developer?",
        "back": "Increase Efficiency, Develop Faster, Less Maintenance"
    },
    {
        "front": "What possible values can be used for the annotation @UI.LineItem.importance?",
        "back": "LOW, MEDIUM, HIGH"
    },
    {
        "front": "What annotation is used to define the heading of list report?",
        "back": "@UI.headerInfo.typeNamePlural"
    },
    {
        "front": "What annotation is used to declare that a field of the projection list contains currency?",
        "back": "@Semantics.currencyCode"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the main characteristics of a search field in SAP Fiori element-based applications?",
        "back": "No value help dialog, Supports fuzzy search, Finda a keyword in multiply fields"
    },
    {
        "front": "What annotations are required to declare that an ABAP Core Data System Supports search capabilities?",
        "back": "@Search.searchable"
    },
    {
        "front": "What property is used in the manifest file, to configure how the selection and presentation variants display using a single variant managment area?",
        "back": "smartVariantManagment"
    },
    {
        "front": "What annotation is used to show fields of the projection list in the general information section?",
        "back": "@UI.identification"
    },
    {
        "front": "What attribute is assigned to the @UI.fieldGroup to add an identifier?",
        "back": "qualifier"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the purpose of a build server?",
        "back": "Provides software that allows continous integration"
    },
    {
        "front": "What goals are chieved by a Lean Development Infrastructure?",
        "back": "Allows for faster innovation through independently released and serial versions of components, Either automates or provides self-service response"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following statements are true when talking about SAP Fiori?",
        "options": {"A": "Is SAP UX that applies to modern user-centric design principles", "B": "is SAP product for implementing SAP Enterprise Portal components", "C": "is SAPs UI Technology for implementing applications for mobile devices", "D": "can be personalized, is simple, and runs on any device", "E": "Sap Fiori provides a consistent and role-specific experience accross all tasks, for all lines of business"},
        "back": ["A", "D","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the vision of SAP when considering SAPs UX direction?",
        "back": "Provide the leading user experience for business applications."
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following SAP Key UI technologies are currently recommended by SAP?",
        "options": {"A": "Web Dynpro Java", "B": "Web Dynpro ABAP with Screen Personas", "C": "Classical Screen with Screen Personas", "D": "Java Dynpro", "E": "SAPUI5"},
        "back": ["B","C","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following are key features of SAPUI5?",
        "options": {"A": "Full translation support", "B": "Web Dynpro extensibility", "C": "Responsive across browsers and devices", "D": "Less open for custom development", "E": "Based on open standards such as, JavaScript, CSS3, and HTML5"},
        "back": ["A", "C","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the key concept of SAPUI5 that enables the separation of information of representation from user interaction?",
        "back": "Model View Controller"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following statements are true of OpenUI5?",
        "options": {"A": "OpenUI5 includes all the main features of SAPUI5", "B": "OpenUI5 contains sap.viz and sap.ui.comp", "C": "OpenUI5 is free for use", "D": "OpenUI5 implements its own Core-Component", "E": "OpenUI5 encompasses the complete SAPUI5 Core, plus many front-end controls that are also included with SAPUI5"},
        "back": ["A","C","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What tool is used to connect the SAP BTP tp an on-premise system?",
        "back": "Cloud Connector"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following parameters must you provide when you create an initial cloud connector configuration?",
        "options": {"A": "Region","B": "Display Name","C": "Subaccount","D": "Password","E": "Location ID", "F": "Description"},
        "back": ["A","C","D"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the initial starting phase of SAPUI5 called?",
        "back": "Bootstraping"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the name of the event that is fired after a successful SAPUI5 Initialization?",
        "back": "init"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the prefix of the HTML Custom attributes of SAPUI5?",
        "back": "data-sap-ui"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following features can be used to describe a module?",
        "options": {"A": "Name", "B": "Association","C": "Definition","D": "Scope","E": "Dependencies"},
        "back": ["A", "C", "E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Which JavaScript function is called to define a module?",
        "back": "sap.ui.define"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which JavaScript function is used to load a module asynchronously?",
        "back": "sap.ui.require"
    },
    {
        "front": "What view type does SAP recommend?",
        "back": "XML"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which function is provided to register a URL prefix for a module name prefix?",
        "back": "JQuery.sap.registerModulePath()"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which class normally used as the base class when implementing a SAPUI5 view controller?",
        "back": "sap.ui.core.mvc.Controller"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following lifecycle hook methods can be implemented by the developer in a view controller?",
        "options": {"A": "onInit", "B": "onRender", "C":"onAfterRendering","D":"onExit","E":"onBeforeRendering"},
        "back": ["A","C","D","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Which layout control can help you group UI Controls?",
        "back": "sap.m.Panel"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the preffered way, when you have the requirement, to hide certain UI controls on a specific form factor?",
        "back": "Assign a standard CSS class, such as sapUiVisibleOnlyOnDesktop of SAPUI5, to the UI control"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which measurement unit is used for the property hSpacing?",
        "back": "rem"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which fragment types are available in SAPUI5",
        "back": "XML Fragment, HTML Fragment, JavaScript Fragment"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following statements are true with respect to fragments?",
        "options": {"A": "Fragments are defined in a manner similar to views", "B": "A fragment itself has a HTML representation", "C": "Fragments are light-weight UI parts", "D": "Fragments need a controller, similar to views."},
        "back": ["A", "C"]
    },
    {
        "front": "When you implement a dialog using a fragment, you should bind the fragment ot the lifecycle management of the consuming view. Which function do you need to call on the consuming view to connect the dialog to the lifecycle managment of the view?",
        "back": "addDependent()"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following model types are supported by SAPUI5",
        "options": {"A": "XML", "B": "JSON","C":"Odata","D": "SOAP"},
        "back": ["A","B","C"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following are binding types supported in SAPUI5?",
        "options": {"A": "Property Binding", "B": "Default Binding", "C": "Aggregation Binding","D": "Elementary Binding", "E": "Element Binding"},
        "back": ["A", "C", "E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Which enumeration defines the various binding modes provided by SAP?",
        "back": "sap.ui.model.BindingMode"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which parameter do you need to provide the ResourceModel() to specify the SAPUI5 module name of the .properties file?",
        "back": "bundleName"
    },
    {
        "front": "The two options provided by SAPUI5 for working with i18n texts?",
        "back": "Module sap/base/i18n/ResourceBundle, Data Binding"
    },
    {
        "front": "Assuming the input language in a SAPUI5 application is de_CH. What is the locale fallback chain useb by SAPUI5 to load the suitable resource bundle file",
        "back": "de_CH->de->en->raw file"
    },
    {
        "front": "What does OData use for resource identification?",
        "back": "URI"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which design pattern is used for resolving relationships between resources?",
        "back": "Hypermedia design pattern"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following return types are supported by service operations?",
        "options": {"A": "Complex Types","B": "Primitive Types","C":"Aggregation Types","D": "Infinitive Types"},
        "back": ["A", "B"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Does the invocation of the getProperty() method on an OData model object trigger a request to the back-end?",
        "back": "No a request is not triggered. The getProperty() method return the current value from the OData model object at the client side. If the value is not available, undefined is returned."
    },
    {
        "front": "What function can be used to check whether Odata model contains changes?",
        "back": "hasPendingChanges()"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which types of components are provided by SAPUI5?",
        "back": "Faceless Components, UI Components"
    },
    {
        "front": "In which file is the Component controller Implemented?",
        "back": "Component.js"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which type of UI Control is used to embed a component into a component consumer?",
        "back": "sap.ui.core.ComponentContainer"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which root element can be used when developing a worklist app?",
        "back": "sap.m.App"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which function invocation is necessary to setup routing inside a worklist app?",
        "back": "this.getRouter().initialize()"
    },
    {
        "front": "How do you catch invalid hases in your routing configuration?",
        "back": "Use the bypassed attribute inside the routing configuration"
    }
]